(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
イッツショウタイム！
It's Showtime!
Hey!
セカイはまだ始まってすらいない
The world hasn't even started yet
Let's go!
魔法使いのキャストも
Even the cast of wizards,
ドラマ背負った怪物も
and the monsters carrying dramas,
いつかみんな いなくなること 知ってる
I know that one day everyone will be gone.
期限切れのチケット
Expired tickets,
経年劣化するハートビート
a heartbeat that deteriorates over the years.
「来年、また来ようね」って
"Let's come again next year," we say,
約束を果たせずに
without being able to fulfill the promise,
もうダメかも
it might be over.
それハウマッチ？
How much for that?
ノイズばっか増える
Only the noise increases.
素直に感動したいよ
I want to be moved honestly,
ずっとそうだった
it was always like that.
錆びた廃屋で夢を見てる
I'm dreaming in a rusted abandoned house.
終わりを越えて ずっとパーティーは
Beyond the end, the party will always,
回り続けるメリーゴーランド
keep spinning like a merry-go-round.
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even started yet.
毎分毎秒ごとにバースデイを
With every minute and every second, a birthday.
地獄の底でハッピーエンドを
A happy ending at the bottom of hell.
セカイはまだ 始まってすらいないぜ
The world hasn't even started yet.
無神経な王様も
Even the insensitive king,
欲にまみれたアルケミストも
and the alchemist covered in greed.
いつか土に還っていく　未練を残したまま
Someday returning to the earth, leaving regrets behind
やばい神かも？　それフェイクニュース？
Maybe an awesome god? Is that fake news?
争いばっか生んでる　知恵の輪ほどきたいよ
Spawning nothing but conflict, I want to untangle the puzzle ring
ずっと不安だった　埃払って再起動する
I've been anxious all along, I'll dust myself off and reboot
Hey! 寿命のすさまじと人生ボー！
Hey! The tremendousness of lifespan and life!
Hey! 星空駆けるジェットコースターを
Hey! A roller coaster racing through the starry sky
Hey! セカイはまだ始まってすらいないぜ
Hey! The world hasn't even started yet
Hey! 最悪で最高な三文芝居を
Hey! A penny dreadful, both the worst and the best
バッドエンド塗り替えるプランを
A plan to rewrite the bad end
Hey! セカイはまだ始まってすらいないぜ
Hey! The world hasn't even started yet
Hey! 終わりを超えてずっとパーティーを
Hey! Beyond the end, a party forever
回り続けるメリーゴーラウンド！
A merry-go-round that keeps spinning!
Hey! セカイはまだ始まってすらいないぜ
Hey! The world hasn't even started yet
Hey! 壊せ予定調和の未来を
Hey! Break the pre-established harmony of the future
鳴らせ再生を告げる鐘を
Ring the bell that announces rebirth
Hey! セカイはまだ始まってすら　始まってすら　始まってすら　いないぜ
Hey! The world hasn't even, hasn't even, hasn't even started yet
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! イッツショータイム！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! It's show time!
イッツショータイム！
It's show time!
はーい！というわけで…
Alright! And so...
ちょっと待って、息切れしてる。
Wait a second, I'm out of breath.
皆殿、こんばんはでござる！見てるかーい？
Everyone, good evening! Are you all watching?
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの用心棒、侍の風真いろはでござる！
Hololive 6th gen, secret society holoX's bodyguard, the samurai Kazama Iroha!
皆殿見てるか？めっちゃコメント見えてる。すご…めっちゃ流れてる。ヤッホー！
Are you watching? I see so many comments. Wow... they're scrolling so fast. Yahoo!
たくさんこんなに動けるようになりました！
I've become able to move around this much!
あのね、先輩たちもね、数多たくさん立っていたこのホロアリーナにね、足をつけ、一曲目歌えたでござる。
You know, I was able to stand on this Holo Arena where so many seniors have stood, and sing my first song.
ありがとう！3Dになったよ！すごいよ！やったー！
Thank you! I'm in 3D now! It's amazing! I did it!
待て、動き回るとカメラさん困らせちゃうから…
Wait, if I run around too much I'll trouble the camera person...
ちょっとまだね、まだ他にもいっぱい来ることあるからちょっと体力残しといて…
There's still a lot more coming, so I should save some energy...
はい、というわけで改めまして、今日は本当に来てくださって皆殿ありがとうございます。
Alright, so once again, thank you so much for coming today, everyone.
今日のことはね、こっち？こっちかな？ここ！ここ！
As for today's event, is it this way? Or this way? Here! Here!
#風真いろは3D でTwitterたくさん呟いてくださいね。よろしくお願いします。
Please tweet a lot on Twitter using #KazamaIroha3D. I'm counting on you.
今日はね、でもなんかたくさん見せたいことがありすぎて、
Today, well, there are so many things I want to show you,
1時間という枠が足りるかどうがすごく心配なんでござるが…
I'm really worried whether the one-hour slot will be enough...
ま、まずはね、早速。やっぱ風真といえばフィジカルということで、
Well first, let's get right into it. Since Kazama is all about physicality,
動いてるところいっぱい見せたいなと思うんで…
I want to show you lots of movement...
いつも修行している道場の方に最初に移動して、
I'll move to the dojo where I always train first,
この鍛錬の様子を見せていきたいなと思います。
And I'd like to show you my training sessions.
それでは、風真の道場へレッツゴー！行くぞ！行くで！わー！
Now then, let's go to Kazama's dojo! Here I go! Going! Wah!
はーい、皆殿お待たせでござる！
Alright, sorry to keep you waiting, everyone!
カメラ、カメラ…カメラが…カメラ？おお、カメラ。
The camera, the camera... the camera is... camera? Oh, the camera.
めちゃくちゃ低いだ。カメラ！
It's really low. Camera!
あれ？風真ちょっとこれちゃんと映ってないじゃね？
Wait? Kazama isn't really on screen properly, is she?
足しか…足しか映ってないでござる。ちょっと！
Only my feet... only my feet are being filmed. Hey!
ちょっと映してくれ、映してくれ。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Hey, film me, film me. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
腰が…腰がしんどい。腰がしんどいでござる。
My back... my back hurts. My back hurts.
まちょっとね、よいしょ。ぽこべーにはまだちょっとカメラマン早かったでござるかな？
Well, just a bit... heave-ho. Maybe being a cameraman was a bit too early for Pokobe?
ね？ぽこべーも一緒に映ろうね。
Right? Pokobe, let's be on screen together.
お父さんにカメラ渡してこっちに来るでござる。
Hand the camera to Father and come over here.
こっちに来るでござる。おいで。
Come over here. Come on.
おいで、おいで。
Come here, come here.
おお、来た来た来た。
Oh, here he comes.
ああ、頑張ったでござるな、ぽこべえ。えらいえらい。
Ah, you did your best, Pokobe. Good boy.
えらいでござるよ、えらいえらい。
You're a good boy, a very good boy.
えらいで、ぽこべえ。えらいよ。えらい、えらい、えらい。
Good boy, Pokobe. You're so good. Good, good boy.
はい、じゃあちょっとね、ここおいで。
Okay, come here for a second.
よいしょ。
Up you go.
はい、というわけでね、皆様改めてまして、
All right, everyone, once again...
今日は3Dお披露目配信に来てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to my 3D debut stream today!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、ちょ、ぽこべえが、ぽこべえが映んない。
Ah, wait, Pokobe... Pokobe isn't in the frame.
イエーイ！
Yay!
見てるでござるか？
Are you watching?
見てますか？
Can you see me?
はい、1曲目でいきなりちょっと歌って踊らせていただいたでござるが、
I jumped right in and performed a song and dance as my opener,
どうだったでしょうか？
but how was it?
可愛かった？
Was I cute?
強そうだった？
Did I look strong?
かっこいいでしょ？
I'm cool, right?
かっこいいってもっと言え！かっこいいって！
Say I'm cool more! Say it!
あはは。
Ahaha.
はい、でね、ちょっと改めてね、風真のね、
Okay, so I think a lot of people
こともっともっとよく見たいって思ってくれてる方々が多いと思うので、
want to get a better look at me, Kazama, now that I'm in 3D,
紹介をね、していこうと思います。
so I'm going to introduce my new self.
はい、で、ぽこべえも見たいでしょ？
You also want to see Pokobe, right?
で、ぽこべえですよ、これ。
Well, here he is!
ぽこべえ！
Pokobe!
可愛い、ぽこべえ。
Isn't he cute?
ちょっと待って、カメラと、ちょ、
Wait a minute, the camera... Hey!
ぽこべえ！
Pokobe!
ぽこべえ、ちょっと待って！
Pokobe, wait a second!
ぽこべえ、ちょっと待って！あはは。
Pokobe, hold on! Ahaha.
ぽこべえ！
Pokobe!
でかい！
You're huge!
でかいよ！
You're so big!
急に...急に大きくなるじゃん！
You suddenly... You suddenly got so big!
どうした、成長期か？
What happened? Are you having a growth spurt?
ちょ、踏まれる踏まれる！
Wait, I'm gonna get stepped on!
風真、踏まれるんだけど！
Kazama's gonna get crushed!
よいしょ。
Whoa.
Yo-ho.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
Heave-ho.
ぽこべえ、急に大きくなったでござるな。
You suddenly got huge, Pokobe.
風真と身長、同じぐらいあるんじゃない？
You're almost as tall as me now!
おお、すごい！
Oh, wow!
ちょ、見て、巨大ぽこべえ！
Look! It's a giant Pokobe!
巨大ぽこべえ！
Giant Pokobe!
ちょ、ちょっといいですか、自分、
Hey, is it okay if I...
巨大ぽこべえ吸い、いいですか？
can I sniff the giant Pokobe?
ちょっと一回やってみたかったんだよな。
I've always wanted to try this.
いいよな？
Is it okay?
はっ！
*Sniff*
はぁ〜。
Haa~.
よいしょ。
Yo-ho.
ぽこべえ、ぽこべえいいぞ。
Pokobe, you're great.
ちょっと一回行くぞ、ぽこべえ。
Let's go one more time, Pokobe.
よっ！
Heave-ho!
ありがとな、ぽこべえ吸わせてくれて。
Thanks for letting me sniff you, Pokobe.
ね、可愛いですよ、ぽこべえ。
He's so cute, isn't he?
どう？
How is it?
あ, 小さくなった。
Oh, he got small.
ちょっと待って、急に自分がスポットライト当てられると、
Wait, when the spotlight's on you suddenly,
何？恥ずかしくなっちゃうの？
what? Do you get shy?
ちょっと小さくなりすぎでしょ！ちょっと！
You're a bit too small now! Hey!
あなた、あなた豆ぽこべえになってますよ、ちょっと。
You... you've turned into a tiny bean-Pokobe.
だめでござるよ、もうちょっと、もうちょっと戻って。
That won't do. Grow back a bit more.
もうちょっと、もうちょっと。
A bit more, a bit more.
Just a bit more.
いつものサイズにね。
To your usual size.
あ、そうそう、
Ah, yes, yes.
いいね、いいね。
Nice, nice.
そのぐらいね。
Just like that.
はい、ぽこべえ堪能した？
So, did you enjoy Pokobe?
あれ、おかしいな。これ風真の3Dお披露目のはずなのに、
Wait, that's strange. This is supposed to be my 3D debut,
なんかぽこべえの方が目立ってる気がする。
but I feel like Pokobe is stealing the spotlight.
ちょっとね、そろそろ風真の全貌も見せていこうかな。
Well, I think it's about time I showed you the full view of myself.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
いえーい！
Yay!
近い！
Close!
カメラめっちゃ近いじゃん！
The camera is way too close!
The camera is so close!
ちょっと待って、あはは。カメラめっちゃ近いんだけど。
Wait a second, hahaha. The camera is really close.
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Hold on, hold on.
ちょっと待って、心のBPMが上がってきてるので、
Wait, my heart rate's going up,
ちょっと一旦準備しますね。ふぅー。
so let me prepare myself for a moment. Phew.
よいしょ。
Okay.
よいしょ、よし。
All right, let's do this.
お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
はい、ちょっとみんな見て、見て見て。どうですか？どうですか？
Okay, everyone, look! Look! How do I look?
いろんなね、方向、方角、方角から見れるようになりました！
Now you can see me from all sorts of directions and angles!
でもいつも前からしか見てないからさ、
But since you usually only see me from the front,
風真の見せたいポイント、ちょっと見てもらおうかなと思って。
I thought I'd show you some points I'm especially proud of.
ぽこべえも置いてね。ね。
I'll put Pokobe here too. Right.
可愛いね、ぽこべえ。ふふ。
You're so cute, Pokobe. Hehe.
ぽこべえも一緒に連れながら、ちょっとね、見てて。
While keeping Pokobe with me, take a look.
見て、これ！
Look at this!
初めて、後ろ公開するんでござるが、ポニーテール！
It's the first time I'm revealing my back... look, a ponytail!
そう、風真のポニーテール、実は結構短めだったんでござる。
Yeah, my ponytail was actually quite short.
ここまでしかないんだけど、どう？
It only goes this far, but what do you think?
そう、最近ね、ちゃんとめっちゃお手入れしてたから、
Yeah, lately I've been taking really good care of it.
今日の3D配信に向けてお手入れしたから、もうつるつるのつるぜよ。
I pampered it for today's 3D stream, so it's super smooth now.
どう？
How is it?
どう？あはは。
What do you think? Ahaha.
ね、いいでしょ？
Nice, right?
あとね...
And also...
ちょっとぽこべえさん、ちょっとぽこべえさん、すみませんね。
Excuse me, Pokobe-san, sorry to bother you.
こちらのほうに来ていただいていいですか。
Could you come over here for a moment?
ありがとうございます。そこで待ってて、そこで待ってて。
Thank you. Just wait right there.
あとね、ずっとね、見せる機会がなかった、この下！
And also, I never had a chance to show this... the bottom!
カメラさん、下のほう。あ、ありがとうございます。
Mr. Cameraman, down here. Ah, thank you.
この後ろの、このツバメのしっぽみたいな。このね、尾びれみたいな。
This back part, like a swallow's tail. Or a tail fin.
これいいでしょ？
Isn't it cool?
ちょっと穴開いてるの、戦った跡で、虫食いみたいに。
These little holes are battle scars, though they look a bit moth-eaten.
ね。
Right?
あ、ここ見えちゃってるでござるな。
Ah, this part is visible.
いいでござる。
It's fine.
ちょっと待って、カメラさんちょっとここ危ないな。
Wait a second, Camera-san, this is a bit dangerous.
ここ危ないな。ちょっと正面からにしよう。そう。
This is dangerous. Let's look from the front. Yes.
あとね、そう、今まで見せれなかったでござるが、
And also, yes, I haven't been able to show this until now,
あとね、この足ね、足、足見て。
and also, these legs, legs, look at the legs.
そう、風真ね、結構薄っぺらい靴履いてたんだよ。足、いや、いい足でござる。
Yes, Kazama was wearing quite thin shoes. My legs, well, they're nice legs.
足の裏も見て。どうでござる？
Look at the soles of my feet too. How are they?
えっ、ちょっと待って、今カメラさんそのまま視線上げたらまずいからね。
Wait, if you raise your gaze like that now, Camera-san, it'll be bad.
怒られちゃうからね。上げちゃだめでござるよ。
I'll get scolded. You mustn't raise it.
え、でもいいでござる。足の裏、初公開。
Eh, but it's fine. The soles of my feet, first reveal.
危ない危ない危ない！危ないよ！危ないよ！
Dangerous, dangerous, dangerous! It's dangerous! It's dangerous!
あーもう、本当危ないな。ちょっと足、足、足、写さないでござる。
Ah, man, it's really dangerous. Don't show the legs, legs, legs.
足、足ね。そう、今までね、見せれてなかったでござるが、
Legs, legs. Yes, I haven't been able to show them until now,
あ、結構、ちょっと、ちょっと、念入りに見すぎじゃないでござるか？
ah, quite... wait, aren't you looking a bit too carefully?
ちょっと、あの、念入りに、念入りに見すぎじゃないでござるか？
Wait, um, aren't you looking a bit too carefully?
そんなに足見る？ちょっと！
You're looking at my legs that much? Hey!
危ないな。ちょっとえっちでござる。だめでござるよ、そんな。
Dangerous. That's a bit lewd. You can't do that.
そう、えっちなのはだめなのでござる。わかるでござるか？
Yes, lewdness is not allowed. Do you understand?
ね。であとね、皆殿めっちゃ気になってたんじゃない？今まで。
Right. And also, everyone was really curious, wasn't it? Until now.
風真がさ、横から見せないからさ、風真のね、
Since Kazama doesn't show from the side, Kazama's...
厚さ！
girth!
バン！バン！バン！
Bam! Bam! Bam!
そう、これが皆殿、これだからね！このサイズが正しいんだからね！
Yes, this is it, everyone, this is it! This size is the correct one!
オッケー？
Okay?
ま、ちょっと晒しでね、ギュッてはしてるけど、
Well, I'm wrapping it tight with a sarashi, but...
今まで触れてこなかった風真の胸筋のサイズは、このようになっております。
the size of Kazama's pectorals, which I haven't mentioned until now, is like this.
間違えないようにお願いします。ふふっ。
Please don't make any mistakes. Hehe.
あ、ではね、本当にね、あの、海坊主ママの衣装がすごく動きやすくて、
Ah, but really, um, Umibozu-mama's outfit is very easy to move in,
こうやって改めて3Dでこうやっていっぱい動けるようになって、めっちゃ動きやすい！
and now that I can move around like this in 3D, it's so easy to move!
うおー！
Whoa!
うおー！やばいカメラさん疲れちゃう。
Whoa! Oh no, Camera-san will get tired.
うおー！
Whoa!
ね、やっと動けるようになって嬉しいでござる。ありがとう。
See, I'm happy to finally be able to move. Thank you.
あ、やばい、ぽこべーも一緒に動かないと。
Ah, oh no, Pokobe has to move with me too.
ごめんね、ぽこべー。置いてけぼりにしちゃった。
Sorry, Pokobe. I left you behind.
一緒に動こうか、ぽこべーも。早いの好きでござるか？ぽこべー。
Shall we move together, Pokobe too? Do you like going fast? Pokobe.
行くぞ！うおー！
Here we go! Whoa!
うおー！やばい、酔っちゃうかな、ぽこべー。ぽこべー酔っちゃうかな？大丈夫かな？
Whoa! Oh no, will you get dizzy, Pokobe? Will Pokobe get dizzy? Are you okay?
あ、酔った。酔った。ごめんね、ぽこべー。
Ah, you're dizzy. You're dizzy. Sorry, Pokobe.
あとね、このステージ、ちょっと今高速で動き回っちゃったんでござるが、この風真のこのいる場所、
And also, this stage... I moved around at high speed just now, but this place where Kazama is,
道場です！道場！
it's a dojo! Dojo!
あ、やばい、ちょっと飛び起きた。やばいやばいやばい。でも道場です。道場、道場。
Ah, oh no, I jumped up. Oh no, no, no. But it's a dojo. Dojo, dojo.
ちょっと紹介していこうかな。ちょっとね、こっちに、
I'll introduce it a bit. Over here,
見て！見て！掛け軸。
look! Look! The hanging scroll.
デデン！健康第一！
Ta-da! Health First!
これはね、風真隊、隊士の皆殿にね、常日頃言われてるでござるからな。
This is because Kazama-tai, the unit members, tell me this all the time.
守ろうと思って道場に掲げています。
I've hung it in the dojo intending to follow it.
あとね、これはね、もちろんなんだけど、野菜生活！
And also, this one, of course, Vegetable Life!
デデン！
Ta-da!
えっ、これ、いいよ、スクショ撮って皆殿。これさ、野菜生活。
Eh, this... go ahead, take a screenshot, everyone. This, Vegetable Life.
あの、野菜、普段足りてない方向けに、
For those who usually don't get enough vegetables,
これを野菜生活をしろという風真からのお達しです。
this is a decree from Kazama to lead a Vegetable Life.
デデーン！
Ta-da!
撮れた？撮った？撮った？
Did you get it? Did you take it? Did you take it?
これを壁紙にして皆殿、野菜食べるでござる。いいでござるか？食べるんでござるよ。
Make this your wallpaper, everyone, and eat your vegetables. Is that clear? You have to eat them.
あとね、兜とかも置いてあったりとか。てか、すごい、いいでしょ？ここ。
And there's a helmet and such placed here too. I mean, it's great, right? This place.
障子感の木漏れ日がね、いい感じなのでござる。暖かいしね。
The sunlight filtering through the shoji screens feels so nice. It's warm too.
でね、あとね、あとね、こっちにね、あ、風真こっち来ちゃだめなの？
And then, also, also, over here... oh, I'm not supposed to come over here?
太鼓が！太鼓があるんだ！太鼓が！
The drum! There's a drum! The drum!
これでいつでも太鼓叩けるぞ。右1キロ、左2キロぐらいつけて頑張ろうかなと思います。ここで練習できます。いやー。
With this, I can play the drum anytime. I'm thinking of training with 1kg on my right and 2kg on my left. I can practice here. Man.
そしてね、そしてね、ここ、今まで見せなかったでござるが、もう一個掛け軸があってね。
And then, and then, here, I haven't shown this until now, but there's another hanging scroll.
ここ！デデン！茄子生活！
Here! Ta-da! Eggplant Life!
ドヤヤヤヤヤ。ま、風真といったらね、茄子でござる。
Doya-ya-ya-ya-ya. Well, when you think of Kazama, it's eggplants.
茄子、毎日食べてるでござるからな。
I eat eggplants every day, after all.
こちらをね、この道場の入り口に掲げさせていただいております。
I've hung this here at the entrance of the dojo.
イエーイ！
Yay!
いいでしょ、茄子。
Nice, isn't it? Eggplants.
いや、やっぱりな、主食は茄子だよな。これに限るでござる。
Yeah, eggplants are definitely my staple food. Nothing beats them.
でも食べる話ばっかりしちゃったでござるが...
But I've only been talking about food...
そうだわ、せっかく道場だし、そろそろね、風真がこう、日々鍛錬してるところを少しでもね、見せたいなと思います。
That's right, since we're in a dojo, I'd like to show you a bit of how I train every day.
って、あれ？チャキ丸。チャキ丸どこ行ったっけ？
Wait, where's Chakimaru? Where did Chakimaru go?
あれ、チャキ丸...
Oh, Chakimaru...
おっ、ぽこべぇ。あ、チャキ丸そっち？オッケー。
Oh, Pokobe. Ah, Chakimaru is over there? Okay.
いや、危ない、危ない。よいしょ。ありがとう。
Whew, that was close. There we go. Thank you.
いや、なくしたかと思ったでござるよ。
I thought I'd lost it.
今日ね、あの、ダンスするからね、外してたんでござるよな。
I'd taken it off because I was dancing today.
じゃーん！チャキ丸！ででーん！
Ta-da! Chakimaru! Boom!
いや、何気に初公開じゃないか？ねえ、初公開でござるよな。
Wait, isn't this the first time showing it? Yeah, it's the first time, right?
見える？この、輝く銀色の刃。ででででーん、ででででーん。
Can you see it? This shining silver blade. Dun-dun-dun-dun, dun-dun-dun-dun.
強そう。用心棒の仕事してそう。でしょ、でしょ、でしょ。
Looks strong. Looks like it's doing its bodyguard job. Right, right, right?
これでね、悪いやつザクザク切ってるでござるから。
I use this to slice and dice bad guys.
今一瞬脳内でザクザクってなっちゃったけど、かっこいいでしょ。
For a second there, I was just thinking 'slice and dice,' but it's cool, right?
かっこいいでしょ。イエーイ！
It's cool, right? Yay!
ね、まあね、ちょっと見せびらかしてるだけで、お飾りかって言われちゃうから、そろそろね...
Well, if I just show it off, people might say it's just for show, so soon...
かっこいいとこね、見せていこうかなっていうことで、今日は訓練道具、実は用意してきました。
I'll show you something cool, so I've actually prepared some training equipment for today.
さあ、呼ぼうかな。風真の訓練道具。ドール？道具。行くぞ。
Now, I'll call it out. Kazama's training equipment. Doll? Equipment. Here we go.
それでは、3、2、1、お願いします！
Now then, 3, 2, 1, please!
うわああああ！目の前来た！木人！
Whoa! It's right in front of me! A training dummy!
おっ？なんだ？回るのか？グルグルグルグル...
Oh? What? Is it going to spin? Round and round...
おっ？おっ？あはははは！ちょっと待って。えっ、これさ...
Oh? Oh? Hahaha! Wait a minute. Eh, this...
ちょっと待って、モザイクかかってんだけど。えっ？
Wait a second, there's a mosaic over it. What?
これ、放送...これ、口に出していいのこれ？や、や、やごー！
Is this... can I say this out loud? Ya-Ya-Yagoo!
えっ、何？風真のいつも使ってるやつに特別出演ってことでござるか？
Wait, what? Is he making a special guest appearance on the one Kazama always uses?
やった！ちょっと記念撮影しとこうぜ。社長木人と。
Yay! Let's take a commemorative photo. With the President Dummy.
行きます。はい、チーズ！イエーイ！
Here we go. Say cheese! Yay!
あ、もうちょっと寄る？このぐらい？
Oh, should I get closer? About this much?
はい、チーズ！あはははは！
Say cheese! Hahaha!
まあね、今こう仲良く記念撮影してるんでござるが...
Well, we're taking a nice commemorative photo now, but...
切るよ、風真は。容赦なく切らせていただくでござる。ね。
Kazama's going to cut it. I'll cut it without mercy. Right.
切ります。
I'm going to cut it.
ぽこべぇ、応援してくれてんのか。ありがとう。
Pokobe, are you cheering for me? Thank you.
じゃあね。かっこいいとこ見せるから。かっこいいとこ見せるから、ちょっと見とって。
Well then. I'll show you something cool. I'll show you something cool, so watch closely.
じゃあ、風真必殺の...
Then, Kazama's special...
風真の型、行きます！
Kazama's form, here I go!
それでは行くぞ。せーの！
Here we go. One, two...
えいっ！
Yah!
決まったー！どうだ！
I did it! How's that?
かっこいいでしょ。かっこいいでしょ。見た？今まで見せれなかったでござるからな、風真がこんなに...
Cool, right? Cool, right? Did you see? I haven't been able to show you Kazama moving...
...かっこよく動いてるところ。やっと見せれたわ。えっ、一体だけ？
...so coolly until now. I finally got to show you. Wait, only one?
まだまだ風真の体力なめてもらっちゃ困るでござる。どんどん来い、どんどん来い！
You shouldn't underestimate Kazama's stamina. Keep 'em coming, keep 'em coming!
木人さん、もっとちょうだい！はい、いっぱい来た！やった！
Mr. Dummy, give me more! Yes, a lot of them came! Yay!
よし、3体。まあ、まあ、3体ぐらい任せるでござるよ。
Alright, three. Well, well, leave three to me.
見ててな、ぽこべぇ。見ててな、みんな。行くぞ。
Watch, Pokobe. Watch, everyone. Here I go.
せーの！行くぞ。えいっ！切れてるか？
One, two! Here I go. Yah! Did I cut them?
はっ！
Ha!
おお、切れた！ちょっと時間差あった。ちょっと時間差あった。
Oh, I cut them! There was a bit of a time lag. There was a bit of a time lag.
よし、じゃあ、行くぞ！
Alright, let's go!
えいっ！
Yah!
とととととと...おらららららら...
T-t-t-t-t-t... Ora-ra-ra-ra-ra-ra...
ぼぼぼぼぼぼ...切れ、切れろ！おりゃあ！
Bo-bo-bo-bo-bo-bo... Cut, be cut! Oryaa!
切れろ！こっちだ。切れろ！おりゃあ！
Be cut! This way. Be cut! Oryaa!
よっしゃ、よかった！ちゃんと切れた。オッケー、オッケー。
Alright, nice! I cut them properly. Okay, okay.
切れた。オッケー、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
I cut them. Okay, okay, okay, okay.
...見たでござるか。体力を使ったでござるが。
...Did you see that? I used up some stamina.
でもまだ、まだいける。
But I can still, still go.
まだいける。
I can still go.
まだいけるよ！
I can still go!
風真はいけるでござるよ！
Kazama can still go!
どんとこい！
Bring it on!
おおっと待て。
Whoa, wait.
うお！
Whoa!
うお、ちょっと待て。
Whoa, wait a sec.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
5か！
Five, huh!
いけるかな？
I wonder if I can do it?
正面、やっぱね、突きとかも見せたいでござるからね。
From the front... yeah, I want to show a thrust too.
突きいこうかな。
Maybe I'll do a thrust.
正面のやつを突き破壊するでござる。
I'll destroy the one in front with a thrust.
できますよ！
I can do it!
それでは。
Well then.
いきます。
Here I go.
いー、よいしょ！
One, two... hiyah!
おっしゃあ！見た？
Alright! Did you see?
見たでござるか？
Did you see that?
他のね、5体も。
The other five as well.
は！
Ha!
おし。
Good.
は！
Ha!
はい！よいしょ！
Yes! Hiyah!
オッケー。じゃあ、いきますよ。
Okay. Now, here I go.
はい！
Hi!
はい。
Yes.
あー。切れたけど。
Ah... I cut them, but...
やつ、まだ地に足がついているな。
That guy... he's still standing.
くらえ！
Take this!
くっ！
Ku!
は！
Ha!
うわあ！強い！
Whoa! Strong!
だがしかし、切れたことに間違いはないでござるな。
But nevertheless, there's no doubt that I cut them.
いやでも見た？
But did you see?
見た？
Did you see?
こんなに動ける風真、見る機会今まで本当になかったし、
There haven't really been many chances to see Kazama move like this until now,
風真も見せられて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいでござるな。
and I'm really happy I could show you.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はぁ。さすがの風真もね、でも。
Haa. Even for Kazama, though.
合計9体？
Total nine?
9体相手にしたら結構疲れたでござるな。
Taking on nine opponents was quite tiring.
そろそろね。疲れてきたし。
Anyway, I'm getting tired.
ちょっとおやつ食べて、ナス食べてね。
Let's have a snack, eat some eggplant.
休憩しようか。ぽこべぇ。
Shall we take a break, Pokobe?
ね。休憩しよう。
Yeah. Let's take a break.
休憩にしましょう。
Let's take a break.
ふぅ。
Phew.
おや？
Oh?
客人でござるか？
A visitor?
ぽこべぇ。
Pokobe.
お？
Oh?
貴様、何奴！
You, who are you!
は！お、危ない！
Ha! Oh, dangerous!
おっとっとっと！
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
危ない。
Dangerous.
なかなか腕が立つようでござるな。
You seem to be quite skilled.
お客様といった感じでもなさそうでござるし。
You don't seem like a guest either.
仕方ない。
It can't be helped.
ここは風真が、成敗してあげるでござるよ！
Kazama will punish you!
いくぞ！
Here I come!
は！
Ha!
ふぅー。
Phew.
あれ？
Huh?
鞘。
The sheath.
鞘、どこいった？
Where did the sheath go?
鞘。
Sheath.
お、おお、鞘。
Oh, oh, the sheath.
あったあった、鞘。
Found it, found it. The sheath.
あー良かった。なくしたかと思ったでござるよ。
Ah, good. I thought I lost it.
まあまあまあ。でも風真にかかれば、
Well, well, well. But for Kazama,
これくらい朝飯前でござるな。ね。
this is a piece of cake. Right?
ふぅ。
Phew.
敵も倒したし、
Defeated the enemy,
今日は頑張ったでござるな、風真。
Kazama did her best today.
ね。頑張ったよね。
Right. I did my best.
ちゃんと頑張ってたでござるよな。
I really did my best.
見てた？
Were you watching?
ね。見てた？
Right. Were you watching?
やべ、ちょっと近すぎた。
Oops, a bit too close.
待って。
Wait.
近すぎた、近すぎた、
Too close, too close,
近すぎた。
too close.
ごめんでござるよ、皆様。ごめんね。
Sorry, everyone. Sorry.
ふぅ。でもちょっとね。
Phew. But, yeah.
頑張りすぎたから、休憩しつつ。
I worked a bit too hard, so while taking a break...
ってか、あれ？
Wait, huh?
お腹空いたけど、さっきナス食べ損ねたんだよな。
I'm hungry, but I missed my chance to eat the eggplant earlier.
お、ぽこべぇ！
Oh, Pokobe!
ぽこべぇ、ありがとう。
Pokobe, thank you.
ナス持ってきてくれたでござるか？
Did you bring eggplants for me?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
じゃ背中に、じゃあそのちょっとね、風真も、もらえます？
Then on the back... can Kazama have some of those?
はい。よいしょっと。
Yes. Up we go.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ね、さっき休憩しようって言って、ご飯食べ損ねたでござるから。
Since I said let's take a break and then missed out on eating.
一緒に食べようか。
Shall we eat together?
ね。風真もセッティングして。
Right. Kazama will set up too.
よいしょ。
Hiyah.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ、せーの。
Then, one, two...
いただきまーす！
Let's eat!
うまい！
Delicious!
やっぱね、ナスはね、生に限るでござるな。
As expected, eggplants are best raw.
ね、ぽこべぇ。
Right, Pokobe?
ね、ぽこべぇも食べた？
Right, did Pokobe eat too?
お、食べたでござるな。
Oh, he ate it.
ん～
Phew...
や、本当にね、色んなことが...
Yeah, really, so many things...
...もうこのちょっとの時間であったでござるしね。
...have already happened in just this short time.
腹ごしらえもしたところで、
Now that we've had a quick meal,
そう、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Right, heave-ho, heave-ho.
ね、実はね風真今回このお披露目で
Actually, for this debut showcase,
どうしてもやりたいなって思ってたことがありまして。
there was something I really wanted to do.
実はこのために舞を練習してきました！
Actually, I've been practicing a dance for this!
えへ、頑張ったんでござるよ。
Hehe, I worked really hard on it.
頑張ったところね、ちょっと見てもらいたくて、
I wanted you to see the results of my hard work,
今日は特別に披露しちゃおうかなと思います！
so I'm going to perform it for you today!
そ、この... ダダン！
So, this... Ta-da!
これを使って、
Using this,
舞を踊っていきたいと思います！
I'm going to perform a dance!
よし、ちょっと緊張するけど
Alright, I'm a bit nervous, but
見てて下さいね、皆殿。
please watch me, everyone.
それでは...
And now...
準備できたみたいなので...
It looks like I'm ready...
演奏、開始！！
Performance, start!!
はぁ～ えへへ！
Phew! Hehe!
あぁ、皆殿、どうだったでござるか？
Ah, everyone, how was it?
練習してきたけど、正直緊張で
I practiced a lot, but honestly, I was so nervous
手、足、つま先、どこもかしこもプルプルだったでござる！
my hands, feet, and toes were all trembling!
ぜひさ、かっこよかった？
So, was it cool?
綺麗だった？ 綺麗だった？
Was it beautiful? Was it beautiful?
可愛かった？
Was it cute?
お、コメントがめっちゃ、めっちゃ... ありがとう！
Oh, the comments are... so many! Thank you!
あ、ちょっとシャンシャンうるさいね。
Ah, the bells are a bit noisy.
ちょっとじゃあ鈴はしまっちゃいます。バイバイ～
I'll put them away now. Bye-bye~
よっこいしょ。はい！
Heave-ho. There!
あぁ～ 見せたかったものもね、見せれて
Ah~ I'm so glad I could show you
風真は大大大大満足なんだけど... そ、あ！ ぽこべぇ！
what I wanted to. I'm so satisfied! Oh! Pokobe!
ぽこべぇ、見守っててくれたでござるか？
Pokobe, were you watching over me?
よいしょ。や、風真ね、
Heave-ho. Yeah, Kazama,
ずっと練習してたからね。
I've been practicing this for so long.
これね、皆殿に今日見せれたよ。ぽこべぇもありがとうね。
I'm glad I showed everyone today. Thanks, Pokobe.
でもね、そ、もう一個ね、そ、もう一箇所ね、
But, right, there's one more... one more place
皆殿をお連れしたい場所があるので...
I want to take everyone to...
行ってこようと思うんだけど、ぽこべぇお留守番しててくれるでござるか？
so I'm going there. Pokobe, can you stay behind?
嫌だ！
No!
嫌だなの？ ちょっとそこは「うん」って言うところでしょう？
You don't want to? Come on, say "yes"!
「うん」じゃないんだよ。大丈夫。
It's not a "yes." It's okay.
ね、また今度連れてってあげるから、今日はちょっとね、待ってて。
I'll take you next time, so just wait here today.
風真頑張ってくるから見てて。
Kazama will do her best, so watch me.
OK? よし。
OK? Alright.
じゃあちょっと風真行ってくるから、ぽこべぇありがとうね。ありがとうぽこべぇ。
Well, I'm heading off. Thanks, Pokobe. Thanks.
あ、ぽこべぇ～ ぽこべぇ～
Ah, Pokobe~ Pokobe~
ちょっと一緒に写真撮ってもらおう。皆殿に。ぽこべぇ～
Let's take a picture together for everyone. Pokobe~
どう、皆殿？ 貴重なぽこべぇとのツーショット撮れた？
How is it, everyone? Did you get the two-shot?
よし、じゃあちょっと行ってくるね、ぽこべぇ。写真撮影ありがとう。
Alright, I'm going now, Pokobe. Thanks for the photo.
よし、というわけで気を取り直しまして、
Alright, so, moving on,
もう一箇所皆殿をお連れしたい場所にお連れします。
I'll take you to one more place I want to take you.
お連れしたい場所にお連れします？ 日本語変だな。ま、とりあえず一緒に行こう！
"Take you to a place I want to take you"? My Japanese is weird. Well, anyway, let's go!
というわけで、Let's go! 行くぞ! うわぁあ！
So, Let's go! Here we go! Waaaah!
ぽこべぇ修行中
Pokobe training in progress
みな殿、お待たせしました！
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
新しいこのステージ来たよ！
I've come to this new stage!
すごいくない？大自然だよ。すごいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing? It's nature. It's great, right?
というわけで歌わせていただきますよ！
So, I'm going to sing for you!
ペンライトいっぱい振ってくださいね！
Please wave your penlights a lot!
快晴
作詞・作曲: Orangestar
Kaisei
Lyrics/Composition: Orangestar
振る準備大丈夫でござるか？
Are you ready to wave them?
できてる？
Ready?
振ってね！
Wave them!
いくよー！
Here we go!
梅雨が明けるまであとどれくらい？
How much longer until the rainy season ends?
まだ紫陽花の光る朝 君の愚痴
Still a hydrangea-glowing morning, your complaints
夏の足音はすぐそこまで
The footsteps of summer are just there
ねぇ迎えに行ってって僕を急かす
Hey, go pick them up, you hurry me
君に言われるがまま路地を抜け
Going through the alleys just as you told me
あの時の坂を越え 虹を越え
Over the hill from that time, over the rainbow
まだ誰もいない夏の空を
The summer sky where no one is yet
全部全部二人占めにするんだ
We'll have it all to ourselves
なんて君は笑ってたよな
That's how you were laughing
遠い夏の記憶
Distant summer memories
もう逢えなくても
Even if we can't meet anymore
二度と帰れなくても
Even if we can't return again
それは美しい 僕らだけの夏だったろう
It must have been a beautiful summer, just for us
さよなら I love you それで全て
Goodbye, I love you, that's everything
終わってしまうような僕らじゃないだろう
We aren't the type to just end like that, right?
変わらないな 空も星も その泣き顔も
Unchanging, the sky, the stars, and that crying face
っていつか君と また笑えますように
I hope I can laugh with you again someday
そりゃ色々あっただろう 今もあるだろう
I'm sure there were many things, and there still are
でも笑いながら生きていく
But I'll keep living with a smile
「それが人生だ」って
Saying "That's just life"
そんな単細胞になれたなら どれだけ良いかって
How good it would be if I could be such a simpleton
過ぎ去っていく日々に意味は無い
There's no meaning in the passing days
なら明日の僕は僕じゃない
Then the me of tomorrow won't be me
そんな筈はないだろう
That shouldn't be possible, right?
泣いていたって空は晴れるよ
Even if I'm crying, the sky will clear up
君が濡らしたってやまないほど
So much it won't stop even if you drench it
足掻いていたって空は星を降らすから
Because the sky will rain stars even if I struggle
まぁ、生きていくよ
Well, I'll keep on living
I know this sky loves you
いずれ全て
Eventually everything
変わってしまったって空は青いだろう！
Even if it's changed, the sky will still be blue!
忘れないさ
I won't forget
でもまた出逢えますように って生きて行くよ
So I'll live on, hoping we can meet again.
君は笑っていて
You keep on smiling.
ふわあああ！
Fuwaaaa!
というわけで、開幕汚い声が出た、
So, a nasty voice came out at the start,
ちょっと待って...
wait a second...
というわけで歌わせていただきました、
And so, I sang,
「快晴」でございました！
it was 'Fair Weather'!
緊張したー！
I was so nervous!
はい、どうだったでしょうか？
Yes, how was it?
そしてね、見て、そう、改めてでござるが、
And then, look, yes, once again,
ちょっと開幕「ステージ凄くない？」って叫んじゃったんでござるが...
I shouted 'Isn't the stage amazing?' at the beginning...
見てください、このステージ！
Look at this stage!
凄くない？凄いでしょう！
Isn't it amazing? It's amazing!
ちょっとまた動き、動きすぎ？
Wait, did I move, move too much again?
凄くない？もう大自然のね、中に作ってもらいました、
Isn't it amazing? They built it right in the middle of nature,
この水上ステージを！
this stage on water!
凄い！月も今日は綺麗だ！
Amazing! The moon is beautiful today too!
そうね、もう本当に大きい滝の前にこうどすって無理やり立ててもらって...
Right, they really went out of their way to set it up right in front of this huge waterfall...
で、風真のお気に入りポイントがね、後ろに風車をいっぱい刺してもらったんでござるよ。見えるかな？
And Kazama's favorite point is all these pinwheels they put in the back. Can you see them?
風真色！風真色！
Kazama color! Kazama color!
いいでしょう？あとはこのね、水上に浮いてる灯籠がね、
Good, right? And these lanterns floating on the water,
なんとも幻想的でしょう、皆様。いいでしょう。
they're so mystical, aren't they, everyone? Good, right?
いいでしょう？どやどやどや。
Good, right? Brag, brag, brag.
はい、そしてね、このもう本当にね、風真といえば「和」ということで、
Yes, and so, since it's Kazama, it has to be 'Japanese style,'
竹やら何やら木材で立派なステージ作ってもらいました。
so they built this magnificent stage out of bamboo and various other woods.
凄い！ありがとうございます！
Amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日はね、残りはここでいっぱい練習してきた歌と踊りをね、
Today, I'd like to perform the songs and dances
披露できたらと思いますので、
I've practiced so much here for the rest of the time,
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね。
so please enjoy until the end.
はい、というわけで、いや凄い、まだ緊張するけど、
Yes, and so, wow, I'm still nervous, but
まだ他にも曲いっぱい残ってるでござるから、見せていきたいと思います。
there are still plenty of songs left, so I'd like to show them to you.
次の曲、それでは皆様、準備はいいですか？
Next song, then everyone, are you ready?
聞いてくださいでござる。曲は...
Please listen. The song is...
ハイドアンド・シーク！
Hide and Seek!
嫌われる事が怖くて 僕は僕は僕を隠した
Afraid of being hated, I, I, I hid myself
誰かの陰口が痛くて 僕は耳を耳を塞いだ
The whispers behind my back hurt, so I plugged my ears, my ears
ハイドアンド・シーク
作詞・作曲：19-iku-
Hide and Seek
Lyrics & Composition: 19-iku-
本当の僕は汚くって きっとみんな僕を嫌うから
The real me is dirty, and surely everyone would hate me
本当の僕は隠しちゃって 綺麗なとこだけ見せてたんだ
So I hid the real me, showing only the beautiful parts
ある日誰の言葉も全部 嘘に聞こえて悲しくなった
One day, everyone's words started sounding like lies and I became sad
そうだ僕の事を嫌うのは 誰かじゃなくて見せたくない方の僕だ
That's right, the one who hates me isn't someone else, but the side of me I don't want to show
今君に もういいかい ねえ まだだよ 本当の僕が恋しくなって
Now I ask you, "Are you ready?" "Not yet." I've started missing the real me
もう一回 呼びかけてみるけどまだ 見つからないよ
I'll try calling out once more, but I still can't find myself
ほら もういいかい ねえ まだだよ そのうち声も届かなくなって
See, "Are you ready?" "Not yet." Before long, even my voice won't reach you
もう一体 僕は僕が誰なのか 分からないんだ
Any more, I don't even know who I am anymore
鬼さんこちら手の鳴る方へ 君は此処にいちゃいけないから
Mr. Oni, this way, towards the clapping hands, because you're not allowed to be here
そんな事告げる僕の方が よっぽど君より鬼みたいだ
Me, who tells you that, is much more like an Oni than you
遠く暗い世界に落ちた 君が最後に一言言った
Falling into a distant, dark world, you said one last word
君が僕を捨てて手に入れる 誰かの愛は
The love from someone else that you'll get by throwing me away...
The love of someone else that you get after throwing me away
見せかけだけの愛だ
is nothing but a facade.
今君に
Now, to you...
もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
"Ready or not?" "Not yet."
僕は誰かに愛されたくって
I just wanted to be loved by someone.
もう何回 嘘に嘘を重ねれば
How many more layers of lies must I pile up
救われるかな
to be saved?
ほら もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
Hey, "Ready or not?" "Not yet."
その内僕が僕じゃなくなって
Soon, I won't be myself anymore.
もう一体 何がしたいのかさえも
I don't even know what I want to do anymore.
分からないんだ
I just don't know.
明日君に打ち明けるんだ
Tomorrow, I'll confess to you
僕は卑怯で臆病だって
that I'm unfair and a coward.
誰かに嫌われる事よりも
I realized that there's something
何十倍も辛い事に気付いたよ
tens of times more painful than being hated.
今僕に
Now, to me...
もういいかい ねえ まだだよ
"Ready or not?" "Not yet."
本当の君はどこにいますか
Where is the real you?
もう何回 君の事を信じれば
How many more times must I believe in you
断ち切れるかな
to break free?
今君に
Now, to you...
もういいかい ねえ もうちょっと
"Ready or not?" "Wait a bit more."
僕の世界が君に近付いて
My world is getting closer to yours.
もう一回 呼びかけてみたら
If I try calling out one more time,
君の声が聞こえた
I heard your voice.
ほら もういいかい ねえ もういいよ
Hey, "Ready or not?" "It's okay now."
その内空も少し色付いて
Soon, even the sky starts to gain some color.
もう一歩 足を踏み出したら
If I take one more step forward,
ほらね やっと 君を見つけた
see, I finally found you.
愛される事を望んで
Wishing to be loved,
僕は僕は僕を隠した
I hid, I hid, I hid myself.
痛んだ傷口を塞いで
Sealing up the painful wounds,
僕は君を君を愛した
I loved, I loved, I loved you.
はい、というわけで、ハイドアンドシークでした！
Alright, that was "Hide-and-Seek"!
よ、さすがにね、ちゃんとダンスをするのに暑くなるだろうなと思って
Whew, as expected, dancing like that made me really hot, so...
じゃん！
Ta-da!
羽織を、上着、羽織を脱ぎました！
I took off my haori coat!
ちょっと何気に初公開なのでござるよな。ちょっとじゃあ、カメラさんに観てもらおうかな。
Actually, this is kind of its first reveal. Let me show the camera.
見てー！
Take a look!
前は意外と3面図とかで見たことあるかもしれないんでござるが
You might have seen the front in the 3-view drawings and such,
ちょっと後ろ見ちゃおうかな。
but let's look at the back.
じゃん！
Ta-da!
こういう感じで開いております。背中がぱっくりだね。
It's open like this. My back is completely exposed.
あ、ちょっと待って、そう。このスパッツね。
Oh, wait, yeah. These spats.
これなんて言ったらいいんだ？
How should I put this?
おへその上までで止まってるでござるから、若干ちょっと隙間があるんだよね。ちょっと恥ずかしいね。
They end above my belly button, so there's a little gap. It's a bit embarrassing.
涼しい！動きやすーい！
It's cool! And so easy to move in!
そう、ということでね、躍らせて歌わせていただいたんでござるが、どうでしたか？
So, I sang and danced for you, but how was it?
いや、ずっとね、ダンスレッスンをね頑張ってやっていて、1曲こうしっかりね
Well, I've been working hard on my dance lessons for a long time,
踊るようになるまでに、練習頑張ったでござるからね。
and I practiced a lot to be able to dance a whole song like this.
見せれてめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！ちょっとね、とちったりもしたんだけど、めっちゃ緊張したー！
I'm so happy I could show you! I messed up a bit, but I was so nervous!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、なんか待ってね、今速報が、速報が...
Oh, wait a sec, there's some breaking news...
あ、なんかTwitterのトレンドが1位らしい！え、すごい！
Apparently, we're trending at #1 on Twitter! Whoa, that's amazing!
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much!
いや、嬉しい！めちゃみんなが観てくれてツイートしてくれてありがとう！たくさん写真撮ってツイートしてくださいね。
I'm so happy! Thank you for watching and tweeting! Please take lots of photos and tweet them!
イエーイ！ありがとう！嬉しいでござるな。
Yay! Thank you! I'm so glad.
なんか頑張ってきて良かったなってめちゃくちゃ思います。本当にありがとうございました。
I really feel like it was worth all the hard work. Thank you so much.
ちょっと待って。水飲んでいいか。
Wait a moment. Can I drink some water?
ちょっと水飲んでいいですか？水飲みます。ちょっと水飲みます。飲む。
Is it okay if I drink some water? I'm going to drink some water. Drinking.
オッケー。オッケーオッケー。
Okay. Okay, okay.
飲みました。
I've had a drink.
いっぱい動いたからな。
I moved around a lot, after all.
まあでもね、風真の体力はまだまだ続きますよ。
But you know, Kazama's stamina is far from exhausted.
そして、このお披露目もまだまだ続きますので、次の曲行きたいと思います。
And since this debut is also still continuing, I'd like to move on to the next song.
次は、特に修行でも練習してたあの曲を、
Next, I've brought a song that I especially practiced
練習してお披露目のために持ってきたので、聞いてほしいです。
during my training for this debut, so I want you to hear it.
それでは次の曲、聞いてください。
And now, please listen to the next song.
心做し。
Heartless.
ねえ、もしも全て投げ捨てられたら
Hey, if I could just throw everything away,
笑って生きることが楽になるの？
would living with a smile become easier?
また胸が痛くなるから
Because my chest starts hurting again,
もう何も言わないでよ
please don't say anything anymore.
心做し
作詞・作曲：papiyon
Heartless
Lyrics & Composition: papiyon
ねえ、もしも全て忘れられたなら
Hey, if I could just forget everything,
泣かないで生きることも楽になるの？
would living without crying also become easier?
でもそんなこと出来ないから
But since I can't do such a thing,
もう何も見せないでよ
please don't show me anything anymore.
君にどれだけ近づいても
No matter how close I get to you,
僕の心臓は一つだけ
I only have one heart.
酷いよ 酷いよ もういっそ僕の体を
How cruel, how cruel, just go ahead and take my body,
壊して 引き裂いて 好きなようにしてよ
break it, tear it apart, do with it as you please.
叫んで 藻掻いて 瞼を腫らしても
Even if I scream and struggle until my eyelids swell,
まだ君は僕のことを抱きしめて離さない
you still hold me tight and won't let go.
もういいよ
It's enough.
ねえ、もしも僕の願いが叶うなら
Hey, if my wish were to come true,
君と同じものが欲しいんだ
I'd want the same thing as you.
でも僕には存在しないから
But since it doesn't exist within me,
じゃあせめて此処に来てよ
then at least come here to me.
君にどれだけ愛されても
No matter how much I am loved by you,
僕の心臓は一つだけ
I only have one heart.
やめてよ やめてよ 優しくしないでよ
Stop it, stop it, don't be kind to me.
どうしても僕には理解ができないよ
No matter what, I just can't understand.
痛いよ 痛いよ 言葉で教えてよ
It hurts, it hurts, tell me with words.
こんなの知らないよ 独りにしないで
I don't know about this, don't leave me alone.
酷いよ 酷いよ もういっそ僕の体を
How cruel, how cruel, just go ahead and take my body,
壊して 引き裂いて 好きなようにしてよ
break it, tear it apart, do with it as you please.
叫んで 藻掻いて 瞼を腫らしても
Even if I scream and struggle until my eyelids swell,
まだ君は僕のことを抱きしめて離さない
you still hold me tight and won't let go.
もういいよ
It's enough.
ねえ、もしも僕に心があるなら
Hey, if I had a heart,
どうやってそれを見つければいいの？
how should I go about finding it?
少し微笑んで君が言う
With a slight smile, you say,
「それはね、ここにあるよ」
"You see, it's right here."
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、『心做し』でした。
And so, that was "Kokoronashi".
あー、コメント欄が泣いてる。
Ah, the comments are crying.
泣かないで、拍手もいっぱいありがとう。
Don't cry, thank you for all the applause.
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ね、ずっと練習してたでござるからな。
I've been practicing for a long time.
こうしてお披露目の時に歌えて
To be able to sing it at my debut like this...
とってもとっても嬉しいです。聴いてくださってありがとうございます。
...makes me so, so happy. Thank you for listening.
いやもう本当にね、ずっとこの3Dお披露目配信のことは言いたくて。
No, really, I've wanted to talk about this 3D debut stream for so long.
でもなんか、連日とかで練習してても、「いや、言えないな」と思いながらどうしようかな...
But even when I was practicing day after day, I was thinking, "No, I can't say anything yet", and wondering what to do...
いや、でも、ずっとこの曲で大丈夫かなって思ったり、
I was also wondering if this song was the right choice...
いろんな思いが交差した曲ではあったんですけどね。
...it's a song where many feelings intersected.
無事皆殿に喜んでもらえて
I'm glad that everyone enjoyed it...
とってもとっても嬉しいです。ありがとうございます！
...and I'm so, so happy. Thank you so much!
心臓バクバク。だけど...
My heart is pounding. But...
もう一回水飲んでいいでござるか？
Can I drink some more water?
ちょっともう一回水飲ま... 水行ってきます。
Let me drink some more... I'll go get some water.
水、水...
Water, water...
やばい。足りてないんだよ、酸素も水も。
Oh no. I'm running low on both oxygen and water.
本当にやばい。よし。
Really bad. Okay.
さすがのフィジカルおばけ風真いろはでも、
Even for a "physical monster" like me, Kazama Iroha,
やっぱね、なかなか全身筋肉痛を超えここまで来たからね、来るものがあるでござるな。
having pushed through full-body muscle pain to get here... it really hits me.
というわけで、そう、今日は楽しんでいただけましたか皆殿？どうだったかな？
So, yes, did you all enjoy yourselves today? How was it?
もうね、あっという間でござるな。楽しい時間はあっという間。
It's been so fast. Fun times fly by.
そしてホロックス、次のメンバーもね、3D化発表されてますね。
And the next member of HoloX to get a 3D model has been announced.
知ってる？知ってるでござるよな？
Do you know? You know who it is, right?
それでは、ドドン！
And here it is!
沙花叉クロヱ 3Dお披露目 6月13日(月) 20:00～
Sakamata Chloe 3D Debut June 13th (Mon) 20:00~
はーい！沙花叉クロヱ！バクバクバクーン！3Dお披露目！
Hi! Sakamata Chloe! Baku-baku-bakun! 3D Debut!
ということで、次は沙花叉！6月の13日、月曜日の
So, next up is Sakamata! June 13th, Monday,
同じ時間20時からありますよー！楽しみだね！
...at the same time, starting from 20:00! How exciting!
すごいね、楽しみ。楽しみ。
It's amazing, I'm looking forward to it.
それにしてもこのサムネイルの「ぺー」やばいな。
By the way, the "flatness" in this thumbnail is crazy.
これ大丈夫なのか？
Is this okay?
ちょっとすごいなんか、いろいろ心配なところもあるけど、でもね、
I'm a bit worried about various things, but...
沙花叉が動いてるところも楽しみでござるから、皆殿絶対に確認チェックしてくださいね。
...I'm also looking forward to seeing Sakamata move, so everyone, please check it out.
一緒に見るぞー！うおー！
Let's watch it together! Whoo!
はい。というわけでね、いや、いろいろあったけど、
Yes. So, well, a lot has happened,
ここまで風真の3Dお披露目見てくださった皆殿、
...but to everyone who watched my 3D debut up to this point,
そしてデビューから今半年経ちまして応援してくださった皆殿、本当にここまで応援してくれてありがとうございます。
and to everyone who has supported me in the six months since my debut, thank you so much for your support.
風真いろはね、ちょっと至らない点が多くたりとか、本当に、あの、いろいろご迷惑おかけしたりとか...
I, Kazama Iroha, have many shortcomings and I've caused some trouble at times...
もう、もう、やらかしまくりでござるが、でもね、でも、この日のために一生懸命準備して参りました。
I've made so many mistakes, but I've worked so hard to prepare for this day.
今からね、この3Dになっていっぱい動けるようになって、これからもホロックス、いや、ホロライブの中でもね、
Now that I'm 3D and can move around so much, from now on within HoloX, and within Hololive,
いっぱい動けるぞってところを見せていきたいと思いますので。
I want to show you all how much I can move.
今後期待して待てということで。
So please look forward to it.
見守っていてくれたらとってもとっても嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you keep watching over me.
そして、また重ね重ねになりますが、
And, once again,
ここまで応援してくれて皆殿、本当にありがとうございます。
...thank you all so much for supporting me until now.
いろんなところをこれから見せていくことになると思いますが、
I'll be showing you many different sides of myself from now on,
これからも風真いろはについてきてくださいね！
...so please keep following me, Kazama Iroha!
というわけで次が、残念ながら、最後の曲になります。
So, unfortunately, the next song will be the last.
この最後の曲は、皆殿がずっと見たい、聴きたいって言ってくれてたあの曲を
For this final song, that song you've all been saying you wanted to see and hear...
ダンスも含めて頑張って練習してきました。
...I've practiced really hard, including the dance.
怒涛の毎日だった、でもこれ踊るために頑張ってきたので、
The days have been intense, but I've worked hard specifically to perform this,
最後までしっかりと見届けてくれたら嬉しいです。
...so I'd be happy if you watched me until the very end.
それでは、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
ファンサ
Fansa
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキッス”で
I'll return the favor with an "affectionate blown kiss"
気のせいじゃない　目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes met
魔法（ハート）作って　恋しちゃって下さい！
Make a magic (heart) and please fall in love!
...て下さい！
...please!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever I can.
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
Throwing myself into challenges with no 'no's.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Hater comments I found while searching my own name.
ふざけんな！誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me! I know better than anyone.
でも大丈夫 ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on stage, everyone is here.
行くよ！
Here we go!
好きになって！ もっと！
Please love me! More!
私を見て！ もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love.
虜にする！ もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！ もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Please enjoy this special night full of love.
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (・ω<)
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write letters to me too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
It's too early for a scandal, but...
裏切りません！ 宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I'm declaring it now.
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんな 実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me, I'll win with my own skills.
だから諦めない 負けず嫌いな私はいる
So I won't give up, I'm right here and I hate losing.
行くよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて！ もっと！
Raise your fists! More!
汗をかいて！ もっと！
Sweat it out! More!
恩返しは 愛のこもったござるビームで
I'll repay you with a Gozaru Beam full of love.
大歓声！ もっと！
A huge cheer! More!
まだまだね？ もっと！
Not enough yet, right? More!
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept this selfish song full of love.
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (・ω<)
はぁ... 終わりが近づく 寂しいね
*Sigh*... The end is near. It's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We'll be able to meet again and again, right?
約束でござる！
It's a promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words that are overflowing with kindness...
心ない誰かの言葉さえ
And even heartless words from someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ
I need them, I need them...
強くなろう
To become stronger.
好きに叫べ！ もっと！
Shout as much as you like! More!
楽しんじゃえ！ もっと！
Just have fun! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Please don't forget, I hope this becomes a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと！
Let's sing together, forever!
共に歩もう ずっと！
Let's walk together, forever!
合言葉は とびっきりのL・O・V・E
Our password is an extra special L-O-V-E!
好きになって！ もっと！
Please love me! More!
私を見て！ もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow kiss full of love.
虜にする！ もっと！
I'll captivate you! More!
夢を見せる！ もっと！
I'll show you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Please enjoy this special night full of love.
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (・ω<)
ふぅー...
Phew...
というわけで、風真いろは3Dお披露目来てくださった皆様、ありがとうございましたー！
And so, everyone who came to Kazama Iroha's 3D showcase, thank you so much!
皆殿のこと、噛んじゃった。
I tripped over my words...
皆殿のこと、大好きでござるよ！
I love you all so much!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
いつも応援して下さりありがとうございますでござる！！
Thank you so much for always supporting me!!
皆様のおかげで3Dになり、たくさん動けるようになって本当にうれしいでござる！！
Thanks to everyone, I've become 3D and can move around so much, I'm truly happy!!
本当に、本当にありがとう。これからもよろしくお願いします。
Thank you truly, truly much. I look forward to your continued support.
隊士たち、大好きですよ！！
My Taishi, I love you!!
2022.6.9 風真いろは
2022.6.9 Iroha Kazama